const quizQuestions20en = [{
    question:"The first patent on carbon electrode arc welding (CAW) was filed:",
    answers: ["by Benardos and Olszewski in Russia in 1882;",
    "by Méritens in France in 1881;",
    "by Benardos and Olszewski in England in 1885;",
    "by Slavianov in the USA in 1887."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"In what situation is the amount of heat consumed by the cathode less than that consumed by the anode?",
    answers: ["When welding with a consumable electrode. When being melted a consumable cathode readily emits electrons which carry heat to the anode, and so there is less heat remained for the cathode.",
    "When welding with a non-consumable tungsten electrode, which, being the cathode, readily emits electrons through thermionic emission. As electrons carry heat to the anode, less heat remains for the cathode.",
    "In arc welding, the cathode always consumes more heat compared to the anode (this is the reason to use preferably the DCEP polarity to take advantage of a higher heat at the cathode for better penetration).",
    "In arc welding, the cathode always consumes less heat compared to the anode because electrons always carry heat to the anode, leaving less heat for the cathode."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"At what temperature does liquid argon exist?",
    answers: ["Minus 110 °C.",
    "Minus 160 °C.",
    "Minus 186 °C.",
    "Minus 196 °C."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"In laser beam welding (LBW) the TEM (Transverse Electromagnetic Modes) are:",
    answers: ["indicators of the spatial distribution of laser power;",
    "laser wavelength curves;",
    "surface defects of materials caused by exposure to the laser beam;",
    "indicators of laser performance (efficiency)."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Mark the true statement about the electric welding arc:",
    answers: ["It is not always the higher the arc welding energy (E = voltage x current / welding speed), the greater the heat input.",
    "Positive electrode polarity is used in processes with consumable electrodes to increase their melting rate, as the anodic region generates more heat than the cathodic region.",
    "The thermal efficiency of an arc welding process is the ratio between the heat input and the total energy generated by the arc (V x I x t). Thus, the greater the arc voltage, for the same current, the greater the thermal efficiency.",
    "The thermal efficiency of MIG/MAG welding with spray transfer is higher than that of welding with short-circuit mode."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Laser brazing has disadvantages compared to furnace or induction brazing processes when:",
    answers: ["the brazing speed needs to be high;",
    "there must be mobility of the heat source (heating);",
    "the reaction between filler metal and base materials is fast;",
    "the reaction between filler metal and base materials is slow."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "},
    {
    question:"The presence of hydrogen in argon + hydrogen gas mixtures used for GTAW/TIG welding:",
    answers: ["can reduce hydrogen embrittlement when welding aluminium;",
    "may allow you to increase the welding speed;",
    "can reduce porosity in welding carbon steels;",
    "can reduce hydrogen embrittlement when welding carbon steels."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The weld metal of two cast iron pieces will have:",
    answers: ["higher tensile strength than the base metal;",
    "higher ductility than the base metal;",
    "higher hardness than the base metal;",
    "less ductility than the base metal."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"When using copper-based covered electrodes for cast iron, the minimum interpass temperature should be of:",
    answers: ["150 ºC;",
    "205 °C;",
    "350 °C;",
    "450 °C."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following procedures should be used when welding fine grained steels?",
    answers: ["Post weld heating at 250 °C, just after welding for, at least, 48 h, to force the H2 to go out of the weld metal.",
    "Post weld heating at 250 °C, just after welding for 2 h, to reduce the risk of martensite formation in the weld metal.",
    "Weld the root with a lower strength consumable, and then, after the weld is finished, the root must be removed by gouging and a back weld must be made.",
    "Post weld heating of fine-grained steels is not recommended to prevent possible grain size growth."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Mark the correct statement regarding defects of the materials crystal lattice:",
    answers: ["Punctual defects of the crystals are of no practical importance because of their small dimensions;",
    "Simple dislocations, edge dislocations, and helix dislocations are only important to justify why the actual strength of the crystals is less than their theoretical strength;",
    "Dislocations are defects that cannot be generated by other existing dislocations;",
    "The grain boundaries are considered imperfections because they separate regions of different crystalline orientations (i.e. grains)."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Mark the correct statement regarding defects of the materials crystal lattice:",
    answers: ["Punctual defects of the crystals are of no practical importance because of their small dimensions;",
    "Simple dislocations, edge dislocations, and helix dislocations are only important to justify why the actual strength of the crystals is less than their theoretical strength;",
    "Dislocations are defects that can be generated by other existing dislocations, through the mechanism proposed by Frank and Read, usually called the Frank-Read Source;",
    "The grain contours are not considered being imperfections because they only separate crystals of different orientations."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Assinale a alternativa correta para evitar a corrosão intergranular dos aços inoxidáveis austeníticos:",
    answers: ["Using as much heat as possible, in order to dissolve the chromium carbides;",
    "Using low carbon base and filler metal (< 0.03%);",
    "Using base and filler metal stabilized with aluminium and/or vanadium;",
    "Heating the material in the range of 400 to 800 °C and cooling slowly."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Assinale a alternativa correta para evitar a corrosão intergranular dos aços inoxidáveis austeníticos:",
    answers: ["Using as much heat as possible, in order to dissolve the chromium carbides;",
    "Using low carbon base and filler metal (< 0.3%);",
    "Using base and filler metal stabilized with titanium and/or niobium;",
    "Heating the material in the range of 400 to 800 °C and cooling slowly."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding creep phenomenon in metallic materials, it is correct to state that:",
    answers: ["In general, ferritic stainless steels have a higher creep resistance than austenitic stainless steels because the former have a crystal lattice with lower atomic diffusivity;",
    "At high temperatures, one of the main creep mechanisms is intergranular slipping. In this condition, coarse-grained steels tend to have a higher creep resistance.",
    "The main creep mechanism is intergranular slipping. Thus, fine-grained steels tend to have a higher creep resistance.",
    "The creep rate is minimal at the primary creep phase, due to a balance between strain hardening and recovery processes."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Nickel alloys can be classified into:",
    answers: ["Solid solution and cold work hardened alloys;",
    "Solid solution and precipitation hardened alloys;",
    "Transformable alloys and peritectic alloys;",
    "Transformable alloys and non-transformable alloys."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"In the TIG welding of nickel alloys one must:",
    answers: ["use shielding gas with the addition of oxygen to increase arc stability;",
    "promote efficient cleaning of joint edges with mechanical and chemical methods;",
    "use shielding gas with the addition of Nitrogen to form beneficial nitrides in the weld metal;",
    "use narrower groove angles (40 - 60 degrees) to reduce angular distortion."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Choose the correct statement regarding phase transformations:",
    answers: ["The phase transformations begin with the appearance of very small particles of a new phase, which grow until the transformation is complete;",
    "The growth of new particles is independent of the ratio of surface energy to volume energy;",
    "Every particle with a smaller radius than the critical one tends to re-dissolve, and every particle with a radius greater than the critical one tends to decrease, since the critical radius is unique to each material;",
    "Anything that influences the increase in the critical radius increases the nucleation rate and reduces the grain size."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What is the most satisfactory welding repair method for malleable cast iron?",
    answers: ["MMA (SMAW) welding.",
    "TIG (GTAW) welding.",
    "Submerged arc welding (SAW).",
    "Oxy-acetylene braze welding (because of a relatively low temperature used)."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following elements would you add to steel to ensure red-hardness?",
    answers: ["Niobium.",
    "Manganese.",
    "Aluminium.",
    "Cobalt."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Zirconium and its commercial alloys are readily welded using the processes and procedure commonly adopted for welding:",
    answers: ["copper;",
    "aluminium;",
    "titanium;",
    "ferritic stainless steels."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Cu-Ni alloys can be hardened by:",
    answers: ["solid solution;",
    "grain refining;",
    "aging heat treatment (precipitation);",
    "phase transformations (through heat treatments)."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Cu-Zn copper alloys (brasses) can be hardened by:",
    answers: ["cold deformation (hardening);",
    "grain refining;",
    "aging heat treatment (precipitation);",
    "phase transformations (through heat treatments)."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Copper beryllium alloys can be hardened by:",
    answers: ["aging heat treatment (precipitation);",
    "grain refining;",
    "cold deformation (hardening);",
    "phase transformations (through heat treatments)."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Choose the correct alternative with regard to welding aluminium and its alloys:",
    answers: ["Fusion welding causes a reduction in joint strength in both treatable and non-heat-treatable aluminium alloys.",
    "Fusion welding of aluminium alloys causes a degradation of the mechanical strength of the molten metal of the joint, but increases the strength of the HAZ due to recrystallization.",
    "The weld regions of non-heat-treatable alloys have low ductility compared to the base metal.",
    "The popularity of high-strength alloys, belonging to the 5XXX series in welded structures, occurs because they have high resistance in the tempering condition followed by annealing."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"When welding low-carbon or low-alloy structural steel to austenitic stainless steel using austenitic stainless filler metal, it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["preheating is mandatory to avoid H2 cracking in ferritic steel;",
    "the Schaeffler diagram is useful for predicting the structure resulting from dissimilar welds only when filler metal is used;",
    "the presence of delta ferrite in the fusion zone favours the formation of a sigma phase if the joint works at high temperatures;",
    "austenitic stainless filler metal (very ductile!) reduces the risk of hot cracking."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"When welding low-carbon or low-alloy structural steel to austenitic stainless steel using austenitic stainless filler metal, it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["preheating is mandatory to avoid H2 cracking in ferritic steel;",
    "the Schaeffler diagram is useful for predicting the structure resulting from dissimilar welds only when filler metal is used;",
    "preheating can be used to avoid embrittlement of the HAZ in ferritic steel;",
    "austenitic stainless filler metal (very ductile!) reduces the risk of hot cracking."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following chemical elements contributes to the J-factor (which measures the temper embrittlement of heat resistant steels)?",
    answers: ["Mn.",
    "Cr.",
    "As.",
    "S."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following chemical elements contributes to the J-factor (which measures the temper embrittlement of heat resistant steels)?",
    answers: ["P.",
    "Cr.",
    "As.",
    "S."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following chemical elements contributes to the J-factor (which measures the temper embrittlement of heat resistant steels)?",
    answers: ["Si.",
    "Cr.",
    "As.",
    "S."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following chemical elements contributes to the J-factor (which measures the temper embrittlement of heat resistant steels)?",
    answers: ["Sn.",
    "Cr.",
    "As.",
    "S."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following chemical elements contributes to the X-factor (which measures the temper embrittlement of heat resistant steels)?",
    answers: ["As.",
    "Cr.",
    "Mn.",
    "S."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following chemical elements contributes to the X-factor (which measures the temper embrittlement of heat resistant steels)?",
    answers: ["P.",
    "Cr.",
    "Mn.",
    "S."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following chemical elements contributes to the X-factor (which measures the temper embrittlement of heat resistant steels)?",
    answers: ["Sb.",
    "Cr.",
    "Mn.",
    "S."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following chemical elements contributes to the X-factor (which measures the temper embrittlement of heat resistant steels)?",
    answers: ["Sn.",
    "Cr.",
    "Mn.",
    "S."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Coating thickness of hot dip zinc coating is about:",
    answers: ["1 micron;",
    "5 microns;",
    "60 microns;",
    "300 microns."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"How can spherical graphite be formed in cast iron?",
    answers: ["By adding Si.",
    "By adding Mg + Ce.",
    "By alloying with aluminium.",
    "By fast cooling during solidification."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which one of the physical characteristics mentioned below might cause problems in case of dissimilar welding of ferritic with austenitic steels?",
    answers: ["The longitudinal elasticity modulus.",
    "The transverse elasticity modulus.",
    "The thermal conductivity coefficient.",
    "The linear expansion coefficient."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The results of welded joint testing by fracture mechanics can be used:",
    answers: ["for determination of component cross-sections of welded structure projects;",
    "for assessment of fitness to purpose of welded structures including information on welding imperfections;",
    "as values required by technical inspection societies;",
    "as values required by future users of steel constructions."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following gases possesses of the highest heating value (kJ/m3)?",
    answers: ["Acetylene.",
    "Propane.",
    "Natural gas.",
    "LPG."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the intensive (intrinsic) and extensive properties of material, it is correct to state:",
    answers: ["The ultimate strength of a material is an intensive property; therefore, its value does not depend on sample size.",
    "The elongation of a material is an intensive property; therefore, its value does not depend on sample size.",
    "The specific heat of a material is an extensive property, therefore its value does depend on the size of a sample.",
    "The hardness of a material is an intensive property; therefore, its value does not depend on sample size."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the intensive (intrinsic) and extensive properties of material, it is correct to state:",
    answers: ["The ultimate strength of a material is an intensive property; therefore, its value does not depend on sample size.",
    "The yield strength of a material is an extensive property; therefore, its value does depend on the size of a sample.",
    "The specific heat of a material is an extensive property; therefore, its value does depend on the size of a sample.",
    "The hardness of a material is an extensive property; therefore, its value does depend on the size of a sample."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the intensive (intrinsic) and extensive properties of material, it is correct to state:",
    answers: ["The ultimate strength of a material is an intensive property; therefore, its value does not depend on sample size.",
    "The elongation of a material is an extensive property; therefore, its value does depend on the size of a sample.",
    "The specific heat of a material is an extensive property; therefore, its value does depend on the size of a sample.",
    "The hardness of a material is an extensive property; therefore, its value does depend on the size of a sample."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the intensive (intrinsic) and extensive properties of material, it is correct to state:",
    answers: ["The yield strength of a material is an intensive property; therefore, its value does not depend on sample size.",
    "The ultimate strength of a material is an extensive property; therefore, its value does depend on sample size.",
    "The specific heat of a material is an extensive property; therefore, its value does depend on the size of a sample.",
    "The hardness of a material is an extensive property; therefore, its value does depend on the size of a sample."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"},
    {
    question:"Paris law:",
    answers: ["gives the cracking speed under stress-corrosion;",
    "quantifies the risk of brittle fracture;",
    "characterizes material regarding fatigue crack propagation;",
    "gives the relation between elongation and contraction."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Paris law:",
    answers: ["shows that secondary stresses (residual welding stresses) contribute to the plastic collapse of the structure.",
    "shows that the location of a crack in relation to the thickness of the material does not interfere with the stress intensification factor;",
    "relates the variation of the stress intensification factor with the growth of a discontinuity under cyclic loading;",
    "relates the metallurgical deterioration of the material to the size of the discontinuity."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"The J-R curve:",
    answers: ["shows that secondary stresses (residual welding stresses) contribute to the plastic collapse of the structure;",
    "shows that the fracture propagation resistance increases as ductile tearing increases;",
    "quantifies the relationship between crack driving force (in this case it is the integral J) and defect extension but only for deep cracks;",
    "quantifies the relationship between crack driving force (in this case it is the integral J) and defect extension but only for shallow cracks."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"When designing welded aluminium structures according to the Eurocode 9, Part 1.1 and Part 2, it must be considered that:",
    answers: ["the V-joint for aluminium has a smaller groove angle than in the case of steel because of the risk of excessive penetration due to a lower melting point of aluminium;",
    "usually, the weld metal strength of aluminium alloy joints is higher than that of the parent metal;",
    "\"the dynamic design is similar to that for steel structures, but with its own parameters \"\"Δσc\"\" and \"\"n\"\".\"",
    "\"the compatibility between filler metal and base metal is important, leading to the definition of a “characteristic strength\"\" (fw) of the joint for different combinations of these.\""],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"When designing welded aluminium structures according to the Eurocode 9, Part 1.1 and Part 2, it must be considered that:",
    answers: ["the V-joint for aluminium has a smaller groove angle than in the case of steel because of the risk of excessive penetration due to a lower melting point of aluminium;",
    "usually, the weld metal strength of aluminium alloy joints is higher than that of the parent metal;",
    "\"the dynamic design is similar to that for steel structures, but with its own parameters \"\"Δσc\"\" and \"\"n\"\".\"",
    "it is necessary to consider the reduction of the mechanical strength in the vicinity of the weld, through a softening factor of the HAZ that depends on the type of alloy, heat treatment undergone and the welding process."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"When designing welded aluminium structures according to the Eurocode 9, Part 1.1 and Part 2, it must be considered that:",
    answers: ["the V-joint for aluminium has a smaller groove angle than in the case of steel because of the risk of excessive penetration due to a lower melting point of aluminium;",
    "usually, the weld metal strength of aluminium alloy joints is higher than that of the parent metal;",
    "it is impossible to ensure compatibility between filler metal and base metal;",
    "\"the dynamic design is similar to that for steel structures, but with its own parameters \"\"Δσc\"\" and \"\"m\"\".\""],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"About the Palmgren-Miner Rule it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["it is applicable to variable amplitude fatigue (and not only to constant amplitude fatigue);",
    "it is assumed that the rate of damage accumulation depends on the stress level;",
    "it is one of nonlinear damage theories;",
    "the load sequence (high - low; low - high) effects are taken into consideration."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"The main disadvantage of the K1C-value in calculating the risk of brittle fracture of steel structures is that:",
    answers: ["this value is independent of crack dimensions;",
    "this value is only accurate for brittle materials;",
    "the experimental value is very inaccurate;",
    "this value is only valid for linear elastic materials."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"About the theories of resistance of materials, it is possible to say:",
    answers: ["Mohr Coulomb's Theory explains the failure of materials by compression and is applied to brittle materials;",
    "Rankine's theory explains the failure of materials by normal stresses and is applicable only to very ductile materials;",
    "Guest's theory explains the failure of materials by shear stresses and is applied to brittle materials;",
    "The theory of St. Venant explains the failure of materials by specific longitudinal deformations and is applicable only to very ductile materials."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"The Bauschinger effect may be defined as:",
    answers: ["a material when deformed by external loading tends to store energy internally throughout its volume;",
    "the location of a crack in relation to the thickness of the material does not interfere with the stress intensification factor;",
    "a decrease in the compression yield strength of the material as a result of prior deformation in tension;",
    "an increase in the compression yield strength of the material as a result of prior deformation in tension;"],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Theoretically, the smallest discontinuity detectable by the ultrasonic test should have:",
    answers: ["dimensions smaller than half the ultrasonic wavelength;",
    "dimensions greater than half the ultrasonic wavelength;",
    "at least 1/4 of the ultrasonic wavelength;",
    "at least the diameter of the small hole of the standard block V1."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"The study of fitness for use of a given component manufactured by welding is applied:",
    answers: ["Only for new structures, as structures in use have additional stress concentration factors.",
    "To structures in use as long as they do not present any weld imperfections, that is, appeared imperfections must be due to use and be present outside the weld.",
    "To structures whose welds present discontinuities detected by non-destructive tests during its manufacture.",
    "To new structures that contain imperfections, to structures in use where imperfections appear or structures at the end of their service life so that an extension of this life can be evaluated."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Which is the highest open circuit voltage (peak value) allowed for welding with direct current for environment with increased hazard of electric shock (as per IEC-60974-1)?",
    answers: ["48 V",
    "68 V",
    "80 V",
    "113 V"],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"One of the non-destructive methods for measuring residual welding stresses is:",
    answers: ["Inspection by eddy currents.",
    "Neutron diffraction method;",
    "Blind hole drilling technique;",
    "Sectioning method."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of these alternatives describes the principle of measuring residual welding stresses by the neutron diffraction method?",
    answers: ["Measuring the resistance to neutron beam propagation, which (resistance) depends on the stress level in the material.",
    "Measuring the attenuation of the neutron beam, which (attenuation) depends on the stress level in the material.",
    "Measuring the variation of distances between crystalline planes and relating it to the stresses acting on the material.",
    "Measuring the variation of distances between atoms of the material and relating it to the stresses acting on the material."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the FAD (Failure Assessment Diagram), it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["A flaw can be analysed by calculating Kr and Lr independently and plotting the result on a FAD. If the point lies outside the failure assessment line (FAL), it can be considered safe, if within it is potentially unsafe. ",
    "This diagram is used for the critical evaluation of components with discontinuities that meet the quality criteria.",
    "The key benefit of the FAD is that it allows the user to apply LEFM (linear elastic fracture mechanics) concepts to the analysis of a structure in which the development of plasticity affects the failure load. ",
    "A point on the FAL (failure assessment line) represents a safe condition, with no threat to the structure integrity."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the FAD (Failure Assessment Diagram), it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["A flaw can be analysed by calculating Kr and Lr independently and plotting the result on a FAD. If the point lies outside the failure assessment line (FAL), it can be considered safe, if within it is potentially unsafe. ",
    "The FAD allows evaluating the occurrence of only brittle fracture of the structure.",
    "The FAD horizontal axis defines the load ratio Lr = P/Pu, where Pu denotes the limit load for the cracked component;",
    "The Lr axis takes into account all factors influencing crack driving force: primary stresses (from self-weight, pressure, live load), secondary stresses (typically welding residual stresses), thermal stresses and stress concentrations."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the FAD (Failure Assessment Diagram), it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["The FAD approach is based on two parameters, usually defined as Kr and Lr. The Kr parameter measures proximity to plastic collapse while the Lr parameter measures proximity to fracture. ",
    "The FAD allows evaluating the occurrence of only brittle fracture of the structure.",
    "Currently, this diagram cannot be applied to the critical evaluation of brazed joints.",
    "The Lr axis takes into account all factors influencing crack driving force: primary stresses (from self-weight, pressure, live load), secondary stresses (typically welding residual stresses), thermal stresses and stress concentrations."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"}]
    
;    